# **Eric Wetzel**

Austin, Texas 78759 | 512-751-6182 <u>ewetzel@gmail.com</u> | <u>ericwetzel.com</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/ewetzel</u> | <u>github/sonder74</u>

# **Summary**

I am a communications professional, content producer, and creative project manager with a background in writing, fundraising, and computer programming. I simplify complex information into narratives for donors, the public, and other audiences. I also have experience working with cross-functional teams and am certified in data analysis and visualization by The University of Texas at Austin.

## **Core Skills**

Leadership, Collaboration with Diverse Teams, Interpersonal Communication, Adaptability, Crisis Management, Writing and Storytelling, Creativity, Digital Fluency

# **Experience**

## Founder and Principal | Wetzel & Company | Austin | 12/2016 - Current

- Provide strategic communications, fundraising, technical writing, video production, social-media
  management, and content marketing services to clients that have included nonprofit organizations,
  major law firms, North America's largest credential-evaluation service, Baylor University's
  entrepreneur-in-residence, candidates for statewide and local office, and others
- Recruit and manage teams of up to 10 web developers, software engineers, graphic designers, search engine optimization (SEO) specialists, data providers, filmmakers, and direct-mail vendors
- Manage donor-communication campaign for a Texas-based affordable-housing organization with 50,000 subscribers, raising and allocated hundreds of thousands of dollars over five years
- Served as senior communications advisor to 2018 Texas Attorney General candidate Justin Nelson, who came within 3.6 percentage points of victory

### Vice President of Communications | Shipley & Associates, Inc. | Austin | 08/2012 – 12/2016

- Directly supervised and mentored up to 15 communications and researchers at award-winning public affairs agency specializing in advocacy consulting, crisis management, and media relations
- Managed accounts belonging to members of the Fortune Global 50 and Fortune 500, gubernatorial candidates, major law firms, trade associations, and the ninth-largest political donor in the nation
- Served as spokesperson and led to positive client coverage in *The New York Times, The Wall Street Journal, The Washington Post*, CNN, *USA Today*, Bloomberg News, Politico, *BusinessWeek*, HuffPost, and other major news outlets, driving legal verdicts and settlements totaling more than \$1 billion

## Communications Director | Shipley & Associates, Inc. | Austin | 08/2004 – 08/2012

- Placed hundreds of media stories on behalf of a technology firm engaged in litigation with 70 major financial institutions, leading to more than \$500 million in legal verdicts, settlements, and royalties
- Wrote proposals that won client contracts worth hundreds of thousands of dollars and annual reports for a \$350 million foundation, successfully managing grantee relations

## Editor | West Egg Communications, Inc. | New York | 11/2007 – 10/2003

• Served as one of the initial editors and writers at Book and Sea Ray Living, a pair of national

consumer magazines covering the publishing and boating industries

- Successfully positioned *Book* as an acquisition target to Barnes & Noble, grew its circulation to 1.4 million, and helped it win a National Magazine Award
- Managed more than 20 staffers and freelancers and project budgets of \$20,000 or greater
- Interviewed bestselling authors and wrote and edited news stories, features, and more

#### **Technical Skills**

#### Microsoft 365 and Other Basics

Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Outlook, Google Docs, Google Sheets, Slack, Grammarly, OpenAI/GPT-4, Associated Press (AP) Style

### Email Marketing and Media Relations

Mailchimp, Mailjet, ActionNetwork, A/B Testing, Prowly, Muck Rack, Business Wire, PR Newswire

# • Digital Marketing, Web Design, and Web Applications

WordPress, Canva, Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Management, HyperText Markup Language (HTML), Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JavaScript, Bootstrap, AJAX, Flask, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

### • Database Management and Data Interchange

Microsoft Excel, Structured Query Language (SQL), PostgreSQL, SQLite, JavaScript Object Notation (JSON), Application Program Interface (API), MongoDB, Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), Apache Hadoop

#### Data Visualization

Tableau, Plotly, Matplotlib, Leaflet, D3.js, Dashboard Setup and Maintenance

#### Programming and Data Processing

Python, Pandas, Jupyter Notebooks, NumPy, SciPy, Visual Basic for Applications (VBA)

#### Web Scraping

Beautiful Soup, Selenium

#### • Machine Learning

Multiple Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Random Forests, Neural Networks, TensorFlow, K-Means Clustering, Scikit-Learn

### Education

Bachelor of Arts in English, Trinity University | San Antonio Senior Seminars, St. John's College, University of Oxford | Oxford, England

### **Professional Certifications**

Certificate in Data Analysis and Visualization | McCombs School of Business, The University of Texas at Austin | 03/2020 - 03/2021

# **Board Memberships**

Board of Directors | The Center for Austin Independent Journalism | 01/2019 - 08/2023Board of Directors | Austin Bat Cave | 01/2012 - 12/2021Advisory Council | School of Information, The University of Texas at Austin | 09/2009 - 05/2010Board of Directors | Friends of Barton Springs Pool | 01/2008 - 12/2009